melissa.com 2019-08-23

# Privacy Policy | Melissa

## EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework

**I. Adherence to Privacy Shield Principles**  
Melissa is held accountable for its information use by consumer privacy expectations and by laws and industry codes established by government entities and industry organizations around the world. The security of your data is important to Melissa Data. We have a 30+ year history of establishing and refining our controls to secure client data in an ever-changing and increasingly connected world. Among the laws and industry self-regulatory codes which Melissa complies in the United States are: 

**II. Right to Access, Amend or Delete Personal Information (Your rights under GDPR)**  
Individual data subjects in the European Union have the right to know what personal data about them is stored in Melissa databases and to ensure that such personal data is accurate and relevant for the purposes for which Melissa collected it. Individual Customers may review their own personal data stored in the databases and correct, erase, or block any data that is incorrect, as permitted by applicable law and Melissa policies. Upon reasonable request and as required by the Privacy Shield principles, Melissa allows individual Customers access to their personal data, in order to correct or amend such data where inaccurate. Individual Customers may edit their Personal Data by logging into their account profile or by contacting Melissa Technical Support by email or phone at: privacyshield@melissa.com or 1-800-635-4772 opt. 4. In making modifications to their personal data, individual data subjects must provide only truthful, complete, and accurate information. To request complete erasure of personal data, individual data subjects are required to submit a written request. Melissa will endeavor to respond in a timely manner to all reasonable written requests to view, correct, amend, or delete all personal data of data subjects. 

**III. Inquiries and Dispute Resolution**  
In compliance with Privacy Shield Principles, Melissa commits to resolve inquiries or complaints about the collection or use of personal data of identifiable data subjects. An individual data subject in the European Union with inquires or complaints regarding personal data or this Privacy policy should contact Melissa at: privacyshield@melissa.com. Melissa is committed to addressing all Privacy Shield inquires or complaints in a timely manner, and to refer unresolved complaints to JAMS Alternate Dispute Resolution, an alternate dispute resolution provider located in the United States. JAMS Alternate Dispute Resolution has been chosen by Melissa as a third party dispute resolution provider. More information can be found at: https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield. If an inquiry or complaint has not been acknowledged or resolved by Melissa in a reasonably timely manner, EU data subjects should contact the above third party provider for more information or to file a complaint. Such services are provided at no cost to the data subject. In addition, in certain and in limited situations, EU individuals may seek redress from the Privacy Shield Panel, a binding arbitration mechanism. 

**IV. United States Regulatory Agencies**  
The EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework is set forth by the US Department of Commerce. The United States Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has jurisdiction over Melissa Corporation’s compliance with the Privacy Shield. 

**V. Third Parties and Onward Transfers**  
Melissa may provide personal data to third parties that act as agents or subcontractors to perform tasks on behalf of and under specific instructions. Such third parties must agree to use personal data only for the purposes for which they have been engaged by Melissa and must contractually agree, through European Commission model clauses and/or similar agreements, to comply with the Privacy Shield principles or another mechanism permitted by the applicable EU data protection law(s) for transfers and processing of personal data. Melissa also may disclose personal data for other purposes or to other third parties when an individual data subject has consented to or requested such disclosure. 

In addition, Melissa may be required to disclose an individual data subject’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. As part of EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and its commitments under European Commission model clauses agreements, Melissa retains its liability and responsibility for appropriate onward transfers of personal data to third parties. 

**VI.**  
Melissa Corporation complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States. Melissa Corporation has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

**Consent**  
By using this site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Statement. Whenever you submit information via this site, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of that information in accordance with this Privacy Statement. 

**Coverage**  
This policy covers how the Melissa Corporation (“Melissa”) treats personal information that Melissa collects and receives, including information related to customer past use of Melissa products and services. Personal information is information about customers, potential customers, Melissa website users, and others who may provide information that is personally identifiable, such as, name, address, email address, or phone number, and that is not otherwise publicly available. This policy does not apply to the practices of entities that Melissa does not own or control or to people that Melissa does not employ or manage. 

**Personally Identifiable Information Collection and General Use**  
Melissa may gather information related to the use of its products and services, registration of a user account on the Melissa website, or in the course of standard business practices. Personal identifiable information (“PII”) is collected from such parties only after obtaining consent, which is obtained when such parties are prompted for information when requesting product information, downloading a trial version of a product, registering a new user account, registering a product, purchasing a product or service, or contacting customer support. Melissa may collect usage statistics to enable Melissa to improve user experience and allocate internal resources. Purchasing Melissa products or services requires a customer to provide certain personal information and enter into a License Agreement. Nothing herein is intended to modify the terms in such a License Agreement. 

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**  
Melissa does not rent, sell, or share personal information that is provided to it under Section 2, except when Melissa has obtained explicit permission, or under the following circumstances: 

  * Responses to subpoenas; court orders; or legal process; or to establish or exercise Melissa’s legal rights or defend against legal claims.
  * Personal information is transferred in the event the product or service is acquired in its entirety by another entity. Melissa shall issue a notification before information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

**Information Collected During Data Processing**  
Information transmitted by users to the Melissa servers as part of data processing functions of its products or services is retained only to the limited extent necessary to complete the associated processing functions of the products or services. 

**User Account Information Use**  
Melissa reserves the right to send certain communications relating to its products or services, such as service announcements, administrative messages, feedback requests that are considered part of routine technical support procedures. 

**Security**  
Melissa takes appropriate steps to protect personal data from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction, whether in transmission or storage. All personnel are trained on the appropriate use of PII and they are retrained yearly with advances in personal security and best practices. 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
Melissa may update this privacy policy as necessary and shall post notifications regarding such updates on its corporate website. 

**Privacy Policy Last Updated: 03/12/2019**
